DANIEL G. CHAPMAN

(510) 961-4708

00d.chapman@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE:

To secure a position within a fast paced, team oriented environment intent on contending with day-to-day challenges, but ready, willing, & able to assist with any unforeseen and/or emergency situations as needed.

Highlights & Qualifications:

- CompTIA A+ Certified.
- 5+ years experience serving in a mission critical environment.
- 5+ years experience with supporting face-to-face, as well as overseas clients via ticketing systems, IM, email, & telephone.
- 5+ years experience of Installation & decommissioning of various servers & networking equipment (rack & stack)
- Install cable pathway systems (cable trays, cable racks, J-hooks or D-rings).
- Install, terminate, test, label and document horizontal, backbone and other cables

TECHNICAL SKILLS (include, but not limited to):

Hardware: Troubleshooting, refurbishment, upgrading, installation, custom builds and decommissioning of desktop/laptop P.C., & servers of the following (but not limited to) manufacturers: IBM, Dell, Hewlett-Packard, and Supermicro.

Soldering, assembly, and custom modifications at the component level, and testing of solar photovoltaic tracing units.

OS: Installation & troubleshooting of the following (but not limited to) Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows 2000, XP, 7, 8, 10, Server 2003, 2008, 2012, 2016, Apple OS X 10.6/10.7/10.8

Software: Remedy Ticketing System, Microsoft Office Package, Norton Ghost, Active Data Recovery, Adobe Photoshop CC.

Networking: Enterprise level Colocation/Data Center client support, Layer 1 network auditing/cross-connection/circuit extension, TCP/IP, cable mapping, tracing, and management.

Exposure: Ubuntu, Fedora, Kali-Linux

DANIEL G. CHAPMAN

(510) 961-4708

00d.chapman@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY:

Self-Employed 01/2013-Current

• Diagnosis and repair of clients laptop, and or desktop systems. This included, but was not limited to system updates, hardware replacement, unlocking systems, virus removal, custom builds, etc.

- Make recommendations as to upgrading hardware, and give advice for tailoring the technology to fit the client's specific needs.
- Assist clients in learning better practices for "safer computing" (not opening email from unknown senders, setting OS/Antivirus applications to automatically update on schedule, importance of creating user accounts for machine access, etc).
- Assembly of photovoltaic tracing units, along with testing & modification, at the component level, to motherboards of photovoltaic tracing units.

Data Center Technician

05/2011-11/2011

Secure Talent (Sub-Contracted to 365 Main)

- Installed, relocated, and/or decommissions hardware including cabinets, shelves, power strips, rails, cable management, servers, storage, printers, and other devices.
- Utilizing Remedy Ticketing software, I monitored customer ticketing queue for new work requests, as well as reviewed all old tickets to ensure that the customers' requests were taken care of, and/or that the customer was being kept up-to-date with the handling of their requests, escalating issues as needed.
- Verified each on-site visiting customer against the customer designated access list, denying entry to any not specified on said list.
- Created daily, weekly, and monthly shift reports detailing summaries of the days/weeks/months events, highlighting escalated issues and unclosed tickets older than 72 hours.
- Completion of all tasks assigned by management and various other daily tasks.

. Data Center Technician

11/2007-05/2009

Opsource Inc. (Sub-Contracted to XO Communications - Fremont, CA)

- IP monitoring for customers, following their preset guidelines in the event of an IP failure of specific IP addresses, documenting actions performed and time spent resolving issues.
- Meet & greet customers as they arrive on-site, helping fulfill any needs that the customer might have & escalate issues as needed to through proper channels, documenting all requests & action taken.
- Completed installation & removal of server racks (2 and 4 post) as well as cabinets, and caged areas.

DANIEL G. CHAPMAN

(510) 961-4708

00d.chapman@gmail.com

- Completing special requests for customers such as, but not limited to: Remote hands work, cross connections between co-locations, energizing new circuits, assisting with troubleshooting network issues.
- Assisted overseas clients with setting up new equipment, and/or troubleshooting issues with newly installed equipment via telephone, instant messenger, and/or email. Again, documenting everything & closely keeping track of time spent handling said issues, escalating as needed.

Service Technician 01/2003 -

11/2007 Transparentpixel.com

- Customer interactions included preparation of quotes for new systems, and/or updating older systems.
- On-the-job training with obstacles as they arise to maintain a broad knowledge base.

EDUCATION

:

The Stride Center - Oakland, CA CompTIA A+ Certification 2013

El Rancho Verde High School - Union City, CA 1997 Graduated class of 1997 with Honors